Code name, D-Day, June 6th 1944
Overlord is a drama, history, war film directed by Stuart Cooper.
During World War II, a young man is called up and, with an increasing sense of
foreboding, undertakes his army training ready for D-Day, June 6th, 1944.
Tom, played by Brian Stirner.
Jack, played by Davyd Harries.
Arthur, played by Nicholas Ball.
The Girl, played by Julie Neesam.
The Trained Soldier, played by Sam Sewell.
Dad, played by John Franklyn-Robbins.
Overlord is a 1975 black-and-white British war film
written and directed by Stuart Cooper.
Set during the Second World War, around the D-Day invasion (Operation Overlord), the film is about a young British
soldier's experiences and his meditations on being part of the war machinery, including his premonitions of death.
The film won the Silver Bear - Special Jury Prize at the
25th Berlin International Film Festival.
“Overlord is not about military heroics; on the contrary, it is
about the bleakness of sacrifice”, Cooper said.
The film explores themes of world war ii, d-day, black and white, london blitz.
The tone is emotional.